www.vivzhang.com (718) 200-2311 | San Francisco, CA Work Authorization: U.S. Citizen

VIVIAN ZHANG

vivian.mzh@gmail.com github.com/vivzhang linkedin.com/in/vivianmzhang

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Strong: JavaScript(ES6), HTML, CSS/ SCSS, jQuery, React, MobX, Webpack, Node.js, Express, MySQL, MongoDB, Git Experienced: Angular, Redux, Backbone, Sequelize, AWS EC2/S3, Docker, Bluebird, Grunt/Gulp, Mocha/Chai

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Front End Software Engineer | OpenIPO

March 2017 - Present | San Francisco, CA

- Work in a team with front-end and back-end software engineers to launch a redesigned OpenIPO main website
- Develop responsive web applications across-platforms using Javascript, SCSS, React.js to improve the user interface and provide an easy and seamless browsing experience for customers

Coding Tutor | Salvation Army

February 2017 - May 2017 | San Francisco, CA

- Tutor students in HTML, CSS and JavaScript concepts and guide them through toy problems and coding challenges
- Introduce coding to young students(12 and under) to inspire them and provide opportunities to start exploring

Human Resources Generalist / Web Developer | Voda Bauer

December 2014 - March 2016 | New York, NY

- Maintained company website using HTML, CSS and Bootstrap, set up agent accounts on OLR and Salesforce
- Set up and maintained employee and agent workstations and effectively provided technical support

RECENT APPLICATIONS

Vinisa | Software Engineer JavaScript | React | MobX | Node | Express | MySQL | Bookshelf | Bluebird | Mocha/Chai | Docker Crowdsourcing-based language learning app

- Architected React components and managed state with MobX for performant rendering and maintainability
- Integrated speech recognition and translation features using Google Speech API and Translate API
- Containerized codebase with Docker and deployed application on Digital Ocean
- Integrated SSL into existing domain to encrypt information across entire application

TubeNotes | Software Engineer

JavaScript | Angular | Node | Express | MySQL | Sequelize

YouTube based platform to create, annotate and share on-screen videos notes in real-time

- Refactored codebase by creating more modular and readable code to increase flexibility and maintainability
- Integrated new features using Angular, Node and Express to enable users to save video notes into bookmarks
- Developed Mocha/Chai unit tests for client-side routes for purposeful Test Driven Development

Friends | Software Engineer

JavaScript | React | Node | Express | MySQL | Sequelize | SQLite

Real-time Collaborative Event Planner

- Constructed RESTful API using Node and Express to serve and store data from MySQL database
- Utilized MySQL and Sequelize to model relational user, events and logistics persisted data
- Integrated transportation feature using Google Maps API to calculate and display distance among users

EDUCATION

Advanced Software Engineering Immersive Program **Hack Reactor**

2017 | San Francisco, CA 2012 | New York, NY

Baruch College B.S. in Finance & Mathematics

Relevant Coursework Algorithms, Computers & Programming I | Advanced Calculus I, II

ABOUT ME

I am a full-stack software engineer with a strong math background who enjoys solving problems and designing algorithms I am also a yogi, a cyclist, a hiker, a snowboarder, a 10 year professional ping pong player, and always, a helper